

Ponyville, Equestria

Summary

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in building distributed back-end systems and infrastructure automation. Mainly focusing on the design and development side of things, but also dabbling in SRE/DevOps practices. I enjoy solving challenging problems (be they of a technical nature or otherwise) and learning new tools and technologies.

Work Experience_

Super Expert IT Solutions GmbH.

City, Country

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar. 2019 - Present

- Designed a service-oriented (a.k.a. microservice) architecture for the company's flagship Customer Loyalty SaaS product, allowing for horizontal scalability, increasing development velocity and drastically reducing the operational complexity (as compared to a similar legacy application).
- Implemented several core API microservices in a cloud-native fashion (leveraging Kubernetes abstractions) in Kotlin, Java and Python.
- Provisioned an easily manageable cloud infrastructure, utilizing Kubernetes on AWS.
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Bitbucket Pipelines, allowing to quickly build and containerize applications (images being stored in ECR) and deploy changes to a Kubernetes cluster in AWS.
- Deployed a centralized monitoring and logging environment (Prometheus, Victoria Metrics, Grafana, Linkerd, CloudWatch, Coralogix), allowing
 to easily monitor the system and locate problematic areas in case an incident occurs.
- Facilitated continuous learning in the team, introducing Kotlin (for writing small and clean server apps), Python (for writing automation scripts and performing load tests) and Kubernetes (for building flexible cloud-native distributed systems).
- Facilitated cooperation in the team, making sure everyone sees the end-goal of the system and not just the piece they are working on, and resolving conflicts between team members.

Depressing Bank Ltd. City, Country

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Oct. 2017 - Feb. 2019

- Implemented a server application for off-line processing of financial data.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins, and helped the operations team to automate their side (development and production environment were completely separate, so the ops team had their own automation).
- Performed a major refactoring of a legacy Java application, rewriting most of it into Kotlin.

Cool Startup Ltd. City, Country

JAVA DEVELOPER

Feb. 2017 - Oct. 2017

- Implemented several microservices in Java for storing and retrieving image data and routing it to processing (text recognition) services, using MongoDB, RabbitMQ, S3 and ElasticSearch.
- Implemented integration and unit tests, performed load testing using JMeter.

Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, Kotlin, Python, basic knowledge of Rust
- Databases/Message gueues/etc.: SQL, NoSQL, RabbitMQ, Redis
- Infrastructure-related: AWS cloud services, Kubernetes
- Other: Algorithms/Data structures, Linux, Docker, Git

Certifications

AWS Certified Developer Associate

CLOUD PLATFORM CERTIFICATION

Jan. 2019

• Learned to leverage the cloud services provided by AWS.

Education

Some University City, Country

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Sep. 2017 - (expected) Jul. 2021

Another University City, Country

B.A. IN JAPANESE LANGUAGE

Sep. 2011 - Jul. 2015